<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>https://cyberroute.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>alessandro.bresciani2016@gmail.com (Alessandro Bresciani)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>alessandro.bresciani2016@gmail.com (Alessandro Bresciani)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://cyberroute.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Presenting Scanme: Deep Dive into Network Scanning with Golang: Building a Port Scanner</title>
      <link>https://cyberroute.github.io/post/2024-02-25-scanme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>alessandro.bresciani2016@gmail.com (Alessandro Bresciani)</author>
      <guid>https://cyberroute.github.io/post/2024-02-25-scanme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: In today&amp;rsquo;s interconnected world, understanding network security is essential. One essential tool in a security professional&amp;rsquo;s arsenal is a port scanner. You probably thinking what? are you reinventing the wheel? Well not exactly I am building a deeper understanding of what happens under the hood.&#xA;There are plenty of tools out there that you can use for network scanning starting from the most famous and popular nmap, you can become a master at using them but have you ever tried to read them and understand the engineering behind?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wannabe Security Researcher!?!?</title>
      <link>https://cyberroute.github.io/post/2024-02-23-rdpscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>alessandro.bresciani2016@gmail.com (Alessandro Bresciani)</author>
      <guid>https://cyberroute.github.io/post/2024-02-23-rdpscan/</guid>
      <description>This is the very first article that I am publishing on this blog, I wanted to share this experience with folks that are passionate like myself about Security at 360 degrees and also share my thought process to actually produce the correct solution. The assignment received has been pretty interesting and at the same time challenging given that I consider myself a wannabe Security Researcher :D. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into it!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://cyberroute.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>alessandro.bresciani2016@gmail.com (Alessandro Bresciani)</author>
      <guid>https://cyberroute.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!!!&#xA;Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Alessandro, Software Engineer in Security, and passionate musician based in Rome, Italy. With over 15 years of experience in the tech industry, my journey began as a self-taught Linux engineer, only later I got into coding and I liked it a lot&amp;hellip;&#xA;Driven by a relentless curiosity and a commitment to continuous improvement, I transitioned into roles as a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE) and DevSecOps professional.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
